Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Soporte Admin Mira en kissasia.cam o kisskh.org
I dealt with very few things,
Me ocupé de muy pocas cosas,
and I'm tired.
y estoy cansado
I'm old.
Soy viejo
Father, you're kidding.
Padre, estás bromeando.
Father, you're in good health.
Padre, usted goza de buena salud.
You're blessed.
Eres bendecido
You're not old.
No eres viejo
Don't flatter me.
No me adules.
I know
Sé
my body.
mi cuerpo.
Father, you're right.
Padre, tienes razón.
You're right.
Tienes razón.
I heard some news.
Escuché algunas noticias.
I'm worried about you.
Estoy preocupado por ti.
What are you worried about?
¿De qué estás preocupado?
I heard
Yo escuché
you're going
te vas
to Xichuan
hacia Xichuan
to look for the Treasure of the Sealed Book.
para buscar el Tesoro del Libro Sellado.
Xichuan is far away.
Xichuan está lejos.
You'll stay there
Te quedarás allí
from dozens of days
de decenas de días
to years.
a años.
It's a long ride.
Es un largo viaje.
Cut the nonsense.
Basta de tonterías.
What are you trying to say?
¿Qué estás tratando de decir?
Yes.
Sí.
Father.
Padre.
I'm trying to say
Estoy tratando de decir
that our Jibei Mansion
que nuestra Mansión Jibei
has the best food,
tiene la mejor comida,
clothing, and use.
ropa y uso.
And we have
Y tenemos
loads of silver and gold.
Montones de plata y oro.
Why do you want to go that far
¿Por qué quieres llegar tan lejos?
to look for the Sealed Book?
¿Buscar el Libro Sellado?
I'm wrong.
Estoy equivocado.
Don't talk nonsense.
No digas tonterías
I don't need the treasure.
No necesito el tesoro.
You know what I want.
Sabes lo que quiero.
Yes.
Sí.
I know.
Lo sé.
[Treasure at Dawn] ♪Reach the highest level♪
[Tesoro al amanecer] ♪Alcanza el nivel más alto♪
♪Reach the state of no desire, illuminate the virtuous light♪
♪Alcanza el estado de no deseo, ilumina la luz virtuosa♪
♪Man is upright because he is moral, and he is strong because he is upright♪
♪El hombre es recto porque es moral, y es fuerte porque es recto♪
♪Upright, strong, and fair♪
♪Recto, fuerte y justo♪
♪I am the fire♪
♪Yo soy el fuego♪
♪Burning out all desires♪
♪Quemando todos los deseos♪
♪River can't put me out♪
♪El río no puede apagarme♪
♪Yang's beginning leads to development. Wu Chi creates Tai Chi♪
♪El comienzo de Yang conduce al desarrollo. Wu Chi crea el Tai Chi♪
♪People are blinded by body and form, letting delusion rule their hearts♪
♪La gente está cegada por el cuerpo y la forma, dejando que el engaño gobierne sus corazones♪
♪People make their own enemies♪
♪La gente crea sus propios enemigos♪
♪Books are all about reason. People are full of purpose♪
♪Los libros son pura razón. La gente tiene un propósito.♪
♪People are overrun by illusions♪
♪La gente está invadida por ilusiones♪
♪They are fascinated by illusions♪
♪Están fascinados por las ilusiones♪
♪With a pure mind, sitting in the clouds♪
♪Con una mente pura, sentado en las nubes♪
♪Watching people creating dreams♪
♪Observando a la gente crear sueños♪
♪Is it painful to live in the world?♪
♪¿Es doloroso vivir en el mundo?♪
♪Learn from nature. Forget all your desires♪
Aprende de la naturaleza. Olvida todos tus deseos.
♪How about clearing all my thoughts?♪
♪¿Qué tal si aclaras todos mis pensamientos?♪
♪Moths fly into the fire♪
♪Las polillas vuelan hacia el fuego♪
♪The fire melts old shackles♪
♪El fuego derrite viejos grilletes♪
♪Today, I know it's me♪
♪Hoy sé que soy yo♪
[Treasure at Dawn]
[Tesoro al amanecer]
[Episode 24] [Siming Sets a Trap, Qianli is in Trouble]
[Episodio 24] [Siming tiende una trampa, Qianli está en problemas]
Chairman Sun.
Presidente Sun.
You found the evidence so quickly.
Encontraste la evidencia tan rápidamente.
But you didn't tell me.
Pero no me lo dijiste.
You don't have any other ideas, do you?
No tienes otra idea ¿verdad?
Chairman Guo.
Presidente Guo.
You misunderstood me.
Me entendiste mal.
I have
Tengo
to make sure
Para asegurarse
before I can tell you.
Antes de que pueda decírtelo.
Besides,
Además,
if we attract the attention
Si atraemos la atención
of outsiders,
de forasteros,
we'll have a problem.
Tendremos un problema.
I see.
Veo.
I thought you didn't want me to know
Creí que no querías que lo supiera.
that you were Song Jingye's horse slave.
que eras el esclavo caballo de Song Jingye.
It's my bad.
Es mi culpa.
I forgot you.
Me olvidé de ti.
I assume
Supongo
you know
sabes
when Song Jingye
cuando Song Jingye
went to the toilet.
fue al baño
Not to mention what plays did he like to watch.
Sin mencionar qué obras le gustaba ver.
Am I right,
¿Estoy en lo cierto?
Chairman Sun?
¿Presidente Sun?
Chairman Guo, you're right.
Presidente Guo, tiene razón.
Let's watch the play together.
Veamos la obra juntos.
Start.
Comenzar.
Bravo.
Bravo.
I've never seen a shadow play.
Nunca he visto un teatro de sombras.
But there must be something wrong.
Pero debe haber algo mal.
Stop.
Detener.
Senior, what are you doing?
Mayor, ¿qué estás haciendo?
It's time for you to sing.
Es hora de que cantes.
Um...
Uno...
We have distinguished audiences.
Contamos con públicos distinguidos.
What are you doing here?
¿Qué estás haciendo aquí?
Senior.
Sénior.
Where is your master?
¿Dónde está tu amo?
Before my master
Ante mi amo
went on stage,
subió al escenario,
he said
Él dijo
he had to go home.
Tuvo que irse a casa.
He asked me to take his place for a while.
Me pidió que ocupara su lugar por un tiempo.
I learned this play yesterday.
Aprendí esta obra ayer.
I...
I...
I don't know the librettos.
No conozco los libretos.
Where is he?
¿Dónde está?
Chairman Sun.
Presidente Sun.
We rented a small house in the back alley.
Alquilamos una pequeña casa en el callejón trasero.
The one next to a locust tree is Meng's house.
La que está al lado del algarrobo es la casa de Meng.
Yin Lie.
Mentira Yin.
Madam.
Señora.
I'll go get him.
Iré a buscarlo.
Go with him.
Ve con él.
No need.
No hay necesidad.
They are useless.
Son inútiles.
Let them take care of you.
Deja que ellos te cuiden.
Leader.
Líder.
I told you
Te dije
we can't trust free information.
No podemos confiar en la información gratuita.
We suffered a great setback.
Sufrimos un gran revés.
Don't talk about Yingying like that.
No hables así de Yingying.
I'm not talking about Yingying.
No estoy hablando de Yingying.
I'm talking about the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion.
Me refiero al Pabellón que captura rumores.
It's the same.
Es lo mismo.
Can you be reasonable?
¿Puedes ser razonable?
Fu Sheng, he bullied me.
Fu Sheng, él me intimidaba.
Feng Qianli's information
Información de Feng Qianli
has never been wrong.
Nunca se ha equivocado.
That's the man we're looking for.
Ese es el hombre que estamos buscando.
What?
¿Qué?
Meng Qin
Meng Qin
resembles Song Jingye in some ways.
Se parece a Song Jingye en algunos aspectos.
Oblique shoulder.
Hombro oblicuo.
Standing posture.
Postura de pie.
Calluses.
Callos.
It's all a result of their training.
Todo es resultado de su entrenamiento.
That person is Meng Qin.
Esa persona es Meng Qin.
He didn't trust us,
Él no confiaba en nosotros,
so he didn't want to tell us the truth.
Así que no quiso decirnos la verdad.
What should we do?
¿Qué debemos hacer?
Let's find a way.
Encontremos una manera.
I have an idea.
Tengo una idea.
What's your idea?
¿Cual es tu idea?
Have you forgotten?
¿Lo has olvidado?
Meng Qin has a 5-year-old son.
Meng Qin tiene un hijo de 5 años.
Kidnap his son?
¿Secuestrar a su hijo?
Wen Jue.
Wen Jue.
How did you come up with such a dirty way?
¿Cómo se te ocurrió una forma tan sucia?
You are the Young Mistress of Xichuan.
Eres la joven amante de Xichuan.
Nonsense.
Disparates.
Can you think normally?
¿Puedes pensar normalmente?
I mean,
Quiero decir,
he's an older father.
Él es un padre mayor.
He must spoil his son.
Él debe malcriar a su hijo.
What about the kids?
¿Y qué pasa con los niños?
Generally speaking, naughty children are healthier.
En términos generales los niños traviesos son más sanos.
Spoiled children are not so healthy.
Los niños malcriados no son tan saludables.
So, Fu Sheng has a chance.
Entonces, Fu Sheng tiene una oportunidad.
You're not married.
No estás casado.
How do you know so much?
¿Cómo sabes tanto?
Because I was spoiled as a child.
Porque me malcriaron cuando era niña.
What do you think, Fu Sheng?
¿Qué opinas, Fu Sheng?
You have a point.
Tienes un punto.
Let's find out
Vamos a averiguarlo
where Meng Qin lives.
donde vive Meng Qin.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Honey.
Miel.
Do we have to go?
¿Tenemos que irnos?
You can't stay in Xichuan anymore.
Ya no puedes quedarte en Xichuan.
I'll get you out of here.
Te sacaré de aquí.
You go out of the city first.
Primero sales de la ciudad.
I'll meet you outside the city.
Nos vemos fuera de la ciudad.
I will wait for you outside the city with our son.
Te esperaré fuera de la ciudad con nuestro hijo.
Just go.
Simplemente vete.
Go.
Ir.
Meng Qin.
Meng Qin.
You have the wrong person.
Estás a la persona equivocada.
I said you had the wrong person.
Dije que te habías equivocado de persona.
Save it for Madam.
Guárdalo para la señora.
Mr. Meng, are you all right?
Señor Meng, ¿se encuentra bien?
Take him back to the clinic.
Llévelo de nuevo a la clínica.
Okay.
Bueno.
Go.
Ir.
Master.
Maestro.
The medicine is ready.
La medicina está lista.
Put it there.
Ponlo ahí.
It promotes blood circulation and removes blood stasis. Drink it.
Favorece la circulación sanguínea y elimina la estasis sanguínea. Bébelo.
Thank you.
Gracias.
My father saved you.
Mi padre te salvó.
We saved you again.
Te salvamos de nuevo.
It doesn't make sense
No tiene sentido
if you don't tell the truth.
Si no dices la verdad.
You're the Young Mistress of Xichuan.
Eres la joven amante de Xichuan.
Thank you, Young Mistress
Gracias, joven señora
and you guys.
Y vosotros, chicos.
I, Meng Qin...
Yo, Meng Qin...
I can't repay you.
No puedo pagarte.
I can only...
Sólo puedo...
Stop.
Detener.
Don't talk empty words.
No digas palabras vacías.
"I'll remember it"
"Lo recordaré"
"and repay you in the next life." It's nonsense.
"y te lo pagaré en la próxima vida." Es una tontería.
If someone does you a favor,
Si alguien te hace un favor,
you should try your best
Deberías intentarlo lo mejor que puedas
to repay him.
para pagarle.
If you can't repay him,
Si no puedes pagarle,
you should admit it.
Deberías admitirlo.
That's what heroes do.
Eso es lo que hacen los héroes.
I learned a lesson.
Aprendí una lección.
So,
Entonces,
you admit you lied to us before, right?
Admites que nos mentiste antes, ¿verdad?
You were the palace guard
Eras el guardia del palacio
my father saved.
Mi padre salvó.
I was seriously injured.
Resulté gravemente herido.
Fortunately, Lord Wen saved me.
Afortunadamente, Lord Wen me salvó.
After I recovered,
Después de recuperarme,
with Lord Wen's help,
con la ayuda de Lord Wen,
I changed my career.
Cambié de carrera.
Before,
Antes,
I didn't mean to lie to you.
No quise mentirte.
I don't want others to know
No quiero que otros lo sepan
that I used to be a guard.
que yo solía ser guardia.
All these years,
Todos estos años,
I've been living a peaceful life.
He estado viviendo una vida pacífica.
But...
Pero...
Can you tell me
Usted pude decirme
what you want with me?
¿Qué quieres de mí?
Why do you have the Bird Jade Plate?
¿Por qué tienes el plato de jade de pájaro?
Why...?
Por qué...?
Why do you have Mr. Song's
¿Por qué tienes al señor Song?
Cloud-shaped Jade?
¿Jade en forma de nube?
You've got all three pieces of jade.
Tienes las tres piezas de jade.
Who are you?
¿Quién eres?
Didn't Song Jingye tell you
¿No te lo dijo Song Jingye?
who the Royal Army was going
A quién iba el Ejército Real
to escort these things to?
¿A dónde escoltar estas cosas?
He did.
Él lo hizo.
We encountered the Raid at that time.
En ese momento nos encontramos con el Raid.
Mr. Song told us
El señor Song nos dijo
that we had to escape alive
que teníamos que escapar con vida
and give these things
y dar estas cosas
to Physician Fu in Shangyi.
al médico Fu en Shangyi.
Are you...?
Eres...?
My name is Fu Sheng.
Mi nombre es Fu Sheng.
The Physician Fu Song Jingye talked about
El médico Fu Song Jingye habló sobre
was my father.
era mi padre
But he's gone.
Pero él se ha ido.
I've been carrying the Bird Jade Plate
He estado llevando la placa de jade de pájaro
since I was a kid.
Desde que era un niño.
You have his Cloud-shaped Jade.
Tienes su Jade en forma de nube.
You must have seen him.
Debes haberlo visto.
Why didn't he tell me about it?
¿Por qué no me lo contó?
He promised my father to meet him at Xichuan.
Le prometió a mi padre que se reuniría con él en Xichuan.
We only met once,
Sólo nos conocimos una vez,
and he died.
y murió.
Maybe he wanted to tell you.
Quizás quería decírtelo.
But he didn't have time.
Pero no tuvo tiempo.
I only want
Yo solo quiero
to take care of my son.
Cuidar a mi hijo.
Physician Fu.
Médico Fu.
As long as my wife, son, and I can get out of the city,
Mientras mi esposa, mi hijo y yo podamos salir de la ciudad,
I promise
Prometo
you will receive something important.
Recibirás algo importante.
I believe
Yo creo
that's what you're looking for.
Eso es lo que estás buscando.
My family is waiting for me.
Mi familia me está esperando.
Excuse me.
Disculpe.
Are we just going to let him go?
¿Lo vamos a dejar ir así como así?
Don't worry. I'll ask Feng Qianli to follow him.
No te preocupes. Le pediré a Feng Qianli que lo siga.
It'll be all right.
Todo estará bien.
Why don't you walk her out?
¿Por qué no la acompañas a la salida?
Leave the door open for me.
Déjame la puerta abierta.
[Jibei Chamber of Commerce]
[Cámara de Comercio de Jibei]
Fu Sheng and Gu Tian
Fu Sheng y Gu Tian
took Meng Qin away.
se llevó a Meng Qin.
Do they know each other?
¿Se conocen?
Ms. Chairman, do you think
Señora Presidenta, ¿cree usted?
it's a coincidence?
¿Es una coincidencia?
I don't think so.
No me parece.
They must have come for the Painting of Luan.
Debieron haber venido por la pintura de Luan.
I thought the same.
Yo pensé lo mismo.
They are aiming at the Treasure of the Sealed Book.
Su objetivo es el Tesoro del Libro Sellado.
I don't know
No sé
how many clues they've gotten so far.
Cuántas pistas han obtenido hasta ahora.
I saw it with my own eyes.
Lo vi con mis propios ojos.
Fu Sheng got the Mountain-shaped Jade
Fu Sheng obtuvo el Jade en forma de montaña.
from the chief of the Tianyi tribe.
del jefe de la tribu Tianyi.
In that case,
En ese caso,
they have
ellos tienen
at least one piece of jade.
Al menos una pieza de jade.
We need to hurry.
Tenemos que darnos prisa.
You don't have to tell me.
No tienes que decírmelo
How long have you been looking for the Bird Jade Plate?
¿Cuanto tiempo has estado buscando la placa de jade de pájaro?
Did you find it?
¿Lo encontraste?
You can't blame me for this.
No puedes culparme por esto.
The bounty notice has been issued for a long time.
El aviso de recompensa se emitió hace mucho tiempo.
But there's no clue.
Pero no hay ninguna pista.
My Lord put the Bird Jade Plate
Mi Señor puso el Plato de Jade de Pájaro
in the bounty notice.
en el aviso de recompensa.
Was he trying to lure someone out?
¿Estaba tratando de atraer a alguien?
Sun Siming.
Sol Siming.
You're getting bolder.
Te estás volviendo más atrevido.
What?
¿Qué?
Does My Lord have to tell you what he's doing?
¿Mi Señor tiene que decirte lo que está haciendo?
No.
No.
Ms. Chairman, you misunderstood me.
Señora Presidenta, usted me entendió mal.
I think
Creo
I know too little.
Sé muy poco.
I'm worried that one day,
Me preocupa que un día,
the Bird Jade Plate will show up,
Aparecerá el plato de jade de pájaro,
and I won't recognize it.
y no lo reconoceré.
I'm afraid I'll delay My Lord.
Temo retrasar a mi Señor.
Just so you know,
Sólo para que lo sepas,
I'm straightforward.
Soy directo.
Maybe I'll say whatever comes into my head
Quizás diré lo que me venga a la cabeza.
when I meet My Lord.
Cuando me encuentro con mi Señor.
Please don't worry.
Por favor, no te preocupes.
Are you threatening me?
¿Me estás amenazando?
I'm not.
No lo soy.
I...
I...
I'm not threatening you.
No te estoy amenazando.
Ms. Chairman.
Señora Presidenta.
You are too thoughtful
Eres demasiado pensativo
and too sensitive.
y demasiado sensible.
We both work for My Lord.
Ambos trabajamos para mi señor.
Don't play tricks.
No hagas trucos.
A traitor ran away.
Un traidor huyó.
The Breakwall took away the Bird Jade Plate.
El Breakwall se llevó la Placa de Jade del Pájaro.
A few months ago,
Hace unos meses,
all physicians in Shangyi
todos los médicos en Shangyi
were poisoned to death.
fueron envenenados hasta la muerte.
That traitor was among them.
Ese traidor estaba entre ellos.
My Lord suspected that his descendant
Mi Señor sospechaba que su descendiente
had left Shangyi for Xichuan
había dejado Shangyi para Xichuan
with the Bird Jade Plate.
con el plato de jade de pájaro.
Physician.
Médico.
Shangyi.
Shang Yi.
Why would the Jibei Chamber of Commerce
¿Por qué la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei
want Meng Qin?
¿Quieres Meng Qin?
Do you remember the bounty notice of the Jibei Chamber of Commerce?
¿Recuerdas el aviso de recompensa de la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei?
They also want to find the Treasure of the Sealed Book, right?
También quieren encontrar el Tesoro del Libro Sellado, ¿verdad?
There is
Hay
no other possibility.
No hay otra posibilidad.
Fu Sheng.
Fu Sheng.
Keep your jade plate
Mantén tu placa de jade
and three pieces of jade well.
y tres piezas de jade también.
I'm afraid they will come at you.
Tengo miedo de que vengan a por ti.
From now on,
De aquí en adelante,
we have to be careful.
Tenemos que tener cuidado.
No. I have to go home
No. Tengo que irme a casa.
to ask my father to watch out for the Jibei Chamber of Commerce.
pedirle a mi padre que vigile la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei.
I'll get some help by the way.
Por cierto, recibiré algo de ayuda.
Why do you want
¿Por qué quieres?
to get some help?
¿Para obtener ayuda?
I'm protecting him.
Lo estoy protegiendo.
Can you
Puede
deal with so many warriors of the Jibei Chamber of Commerce?
¿Cómo lidiar con tantos guerreros de la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei?
Besides,
Además,
you almost got beheaded last time.
La última vez casi te decapitan.
I'll leave.
Me voy.
I'm telling you.
Te lo digo.
You have to educate her.
Tienes que educarla.
She always rubs it in my face.
Ella siempre me lo restriega en la cara.
I have a reputation.
Tengo una reputación.
Do you think I can help you with this?
¿Crees que puedo ayudarte con esto?
You'd better tell her yourself.
Será mejor que se lo digas tú mismo.
You lost control of your wife.
Perdiste el control de tu esposa.
They are hiding it well.
Lo están ocultando bien.
What's wrong?
¿Qué ocurre?
What are you thinking about?
¿En qué estás pensando?
Ms. Chairman, you don't know.
Señora Presidenta, usted no lo sabe.
Fu Sheng and Gu Tian are from Shangyi.
Fu Sheng y Gu Tian son de Shangyi.
I didn't expect them to come out like this.
No esperaba que salieran así.
I went through all this trouble.
Pasé por todos estos problemas.
But the Bird Jade Plate is just around the corner.
Pero el plato de jade de pájaro está a la vuelta de la esquina.
Fu Sheng has the Bird Jade Plate?
¿Fu Sheng tiene la placa de jade de pájaro?
Are you sure?
¿Está seguro?
There's a good chance
Hay una buena posibilidad
he has it.
Él lo tiene.
It's not just the jade plate.
No es sólo la placa de jade.
I'm afraid
Me temo que
he has the three pieces of jade.
Él tiene las tres piezas de jade.
Yin Lie.
Mentira Yin.
Go get him.
Ve a buscarlo.
Yin.
Haciendo.
Wait.
Esperar.
Ms. Chairman.
Señora Presidenta.
If we go catch him,
Si vamos a atraparlo,
we're
eran
declaring war on Lord Wen.
declarando la guerra a Lord Wen.
If the Ma Gang gets involved,
Si la pandilla Ma se involucra,
we have a problem.
Tenemos un problema.
I have an idea.
Tengo una idea.
I'm not sure if it will work.
No estoy seguro de si funcionará.
Stop.
Detener.
Gentlemen,
Caballeros,
please stop.
Por favor, deténgase.
We don't know where Meng Qin is.
No sabemos dónde está Meng Qin.
There's a thief in your troupe.
Hay un ladrón en tu troupe.
He stole from our Jibei Chamber of Commerce.
Él robó de nuestra Cámara de Comercio de Jibei.
I'm telling you.
Te lo digo.
You'd better tell me where Meng Qin is.
Será mejor que me digas dónde está Meng Qin.
Otherwise,
De lo contrario,
you'll end up like this.
Terminarás así.
[Xichuan City]
[Ciudad de Xichuan]
Stop.
Detener.
What's in the basket?
¿Qué hay en la cesta?
Go.
Ir.
Stop.
Detener.
Let me check.
Permítame verificar.
What's wrong with you?
¿Qué sucede contigo?
There he is. Chase.
Ahí está. Chase.
Mother, it's father.
Madre, es padre.
Arrest them.
Arréstenlos.
Chase.
Perseguir.
Search.
Buscar.
- Yes. - Yes.
- Sí. - Sí.
Don't speak.
No hables
The Jibei Chamber of Commerce said
La Cámara de Comercio de Jibei dijo
an actor stole from them.
Un actor les robó.
They're searching the city for you.
Te están buscando por toda la ciudad.
They got your wife and son.
Se llevaron a tu esposa y a tu hijo.
Don't move.
No te muevas
If you trust me, Feng Qianli,
Si confías en mí, Feng Qianli
and the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion,
y el Pabellón que Captura Rumores,
do what I say.
Haz lo que te digo.
You guys, go there.
Ustedes, vayan allí.
Come with me.
Venga conmigo.
- No. - No.
- No. - No.
[Mingxiang Tea Shop]
[Tienda de té Mingxiang]
Search.
Buscar.
Yes.
Sí.
Master Yin.
Maestro Yin.
No.
No.
Who are you?
¿Quién eres?
What they're saying
Lo que están diciendo
sounds good,
suena bien,
like you're about to meet a god,
como si estuvieras a punto de conocer a un dios,
but when you look for it, it's as vague as the wind or a shadow,
pero cuando lo buscas, es tan vago como el viento o una sombra,
as impossible to get.
tan imposible de conseguir.
What are you talking about?
¿De qué estás hablando?
Master Yin.
Maestro Yin.
He's the owner of the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion,
Es el dueño del Pabellón de Captura de Rumores,
Feng Qianli.
Feng Qian Li.
Hearsay-capturing Pavilion?
¿Un pabellón que captura rumores?
Hand him over.
Entrégueselo.
Otherwise,
De lo contrario,
I'll have to hurt you.
Tendré que hacerte daño.
The man the Jibei Chamber of Commerce is looking for
El hombre que busca la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei
is not here.
no esta aqui
General, if you have time,
General, si tiene tiempo,
how about
¿Qué tal?
sitting down and having some tea?
¿Sentarse y tomar un té?
I saw him run into this alley with my own eyes.
Lo vi correr hacia este callejón con mis propios ojos.
There's a good chance
Hay una buena posibilidad
he's hiding here.
Él se esconde aquí.
You'd better hand him over.
Será mejor que lo entregues.
Otherwise,
De lo contrario,
I'll destroy your place.
Destruiré tu lugar.
It's as simple as stepping on an ant.
Es tan simple como pisar una hormiga.
It seems that the Jibei Chamber of Commerce
Parece que la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei
wants to compete for the position of city lord.
quiere competir por el puesto de señor de la ciudad.
If I sell the information to the Lord's Mansion or the Ma Gang,
Si vendo la información a la Mansión del Señor o a Ma Gang,
I might be able to make some money.
Quizás pueda ganar algo de dinero.
I'm not Sun Siming's man.
No soy el hombre de Sun Siming.
We are the Jibei Army.
Somos el Ejército Jibei.
Don't tell us what to do.
No nos digas qué hacer
I don't care who you are.
No me importa quién seas.
You're in Xichuan.
Estás en Xichuan.
You have to abide by the rules of Xichuan.
Tienes que respetar las reglas de Xichuan.
Anyone who breaks the rules
Cualquiera que rompa las reglas
can't leave here.
No puedo irme de aquí.
Okay.
Bueno.
Let me see which one of us
Déjame ver cuál de nosotros
can't get out of here.
No puedo salir de aquí.
Arrest him.
Arréstalo.
Wait.
Esperar.
What are you, the Jibei Army, doing here?
¿Qué están haciendo ustedes, el Ejército Jibei, aquí?
You can fool others,
Puedes engañar a los demás,
but you can't fool the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion.
Pero no puedes engañar al Pabellón que captura los rumores.
If I die
Si muero
or am arrested by you,
o soy arrestado por ti,
I promise
Prometo
everyone in Xichuan
Todos en Xichuan
will hear this secret
escuchará este secreto
within four hours.
dentro de cuatro horas.
Master Yin.
Maestro Yin.
The Hearsay-capturing Pavilion
El pabellón que captura rumores
is a force to be reckoned within the city.
Es una fuerza a tener en cuenta dentro de la ciudad.
If we get Chairman Guo in trouble...
Si metemos en problemas al presidente Guo...
I'll let you go this time.
Te dejaré ir esta vez.
If I see you again,
Si te vuelvo a ver,
I won't let you go.
No te dejaré ir.
Go.
Ir.
See you.
Nos vemos.
Mr. Feng, thank you for saving me.
Señor Feng, gracias por salvarme.
I want to go to the Wenfu Hall.
Quiero ir al Salón Wenfu.
Can you take me there?
¿Puedes llevarme allí?
[Wenfu Hall]
[Salón Wenfu]
We've been busy all day.
Hemos estado ocupados todo el día.
Help Hulu with the medicine.
Ayuda a Hulu con la medicina.
I might as well visit Yingying.
También podría visitar Yingying.
Who pissed you off?
¿Quién te hizo enojar?
What's wrong?
¿Qué ocurre?
My father wouldn't lend people to me.
Mi padre no me prestaba gente.
He said that although Sun Siming was a rat,
Dijo que aunque Sun Siming era una rata,
he was smart,
Él era inteligente,
and he acted only behind your back.
y actuó sólo a tus espaldas.
If you don't mess with him,
Si no te metes con él,
he won't do anything to us.
Él no nos hará nada.
Stay in the clinic.
Permanecer en la clínica.
Don't go out.
No salgas.
Are we going to stay here forever?
¿Nos quedaremos aquí para siempre?
Sister.
Hermana.
Hulu.
Hulu.
Close the door.
Cierre la puerta.
Yingying.
Yingying.
I was going to meet you.
Iba a conocerte.
Have a seat.
Toma asiento.
Mr. Meng.
Sr. Meng
Physician Fu.
Médico Fu.
The Jibei Chamber of Commerce wants me in the city.
La Cámara de Comercio de Jibei me quiere en la ciudad.
I'm here to ask for help.
Estoy aquí para pedir ayuda.
Tell us what you need us to do.
Cuéntanos qué necesitas que hagamos.
Before that,
Antes de eso,
I have to tell you some secrets.
Tengo que contarte algunos secretos.
I recognized Mr. Song
Reconocí al señor Song.
in a performance
en una actuación
more than a decade ago.
Hace más de una década.
At that time, he was already the Chairman of the Jibei Chamber of Commerce.
En ese momento, ya era presidente de la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei.
For our safety, we agreed
Por nuestra seguridad, acordamos
not to meet each other
no encontrarse
unless something big happened.
A menos que algo grande sucediera.
After Mr. Song died,
Después de la muerte del Sr. Song,
I knew something was wrong.
Sabía que algo andaba mal.
But I didn't dare to act rashly.
Pero no me atreví a actuar precipitadamente.
I was afraid that someone would follow the lead and find me.
Tenía miedo de que alguien siguiera mi pista y me encontrara.
Because...
Porque...
I was in charge
Yo estaba a cargo
of the Painting of Luan, which indicates the location
de la Pintura de Luan, que indica la ubicación
of the Treasure of the Sealed Book.
del Tesoro del Libro Sellado.
The Painting of Luan?
¿La pintura de Luan?
Twenty years ago,
Hace veinte años,
on the night of Jibei King's wedding,
En la noche de la boda del Rey Jibei,
there was a rebellion in the Jibei Palace.
Hubo una rebelión en el Palacio Jibei.
I heard that Liu Luan, the Jibei King,
Escuché que Liu Luan, el Rey Jibei,
was seriously injured that night.
Resultó gravemente herido esa noche.
Our Royal Army
Nuestro Ejército Real
was suddenly given a secret mission
De repente le dieron una misión secreta
to immediately go to a wasteland and wait.
ir inmediatamente a un páramo y esperar.
What were you waiting for?
¿Qué estabas esperando?
I don't know.
No sé.
Dozens of us rode horses
Docenas de nosotros montamos a caballo
for four days
durante cuatro días
to reach the wasteland outside Xichuan.
para llegar al desierto fuera de Xichuan.
After we arrived,
Después de que llegamos,
Mr. Song asked us not to talk
El señor Song nos pidió que no habláramos.
or light a fire.
o encender un fuego.
The next evening,
La noche siguiente,
a eunuch came with a bag.
Un eunuco vino con una bolsa.
He handed the bag to Mr. Song
Le entregó la bolsa al señor Song.
and killed himself.
y se suicidó.
The Bird Jade Plate and the Painting of Luan
El plato de jade de pájaro y la pintura de Luan
were in the bag, right?
Estaban en la bolsa, ¿verdad?
Exactly.
Exactamente.
Mr. Song told us
El señor Song nos dijo
that the bag was the only key
que la bolsa era la única llave
to the Treasure of the Sealed Book.
al Tesoro del Libro Sellado.
He asked us to be sure to hand it to Physician Fu in Shangyi.
Nos pidió que nos aseguráramos de entregárselo al médico Fu en Shangyi.
So, we headed to Shangyi.
Entonces nos dirigimos a Shangyi.
We didn't expect
No esperábamos
to encounter the Raid outside Xichuan.
para encontrarse con el Raid en las afueras de Xichuan.
It was my father.
Era mi padre.
Yes.
Sí.
I was holding the Painting of Luan.
Estaba sosteniendo la pintura de Luan.
I thought I was going to die.
Creí que iba a morir.
I didn't expect Lord Wen to be so kind.
No esperaba que Lord Wen fuera tan amable.
He helped me change my career
Él me ayudó a cambiar de carrera.
and live in Xichuan.
y vivir en Xichuan.
Wait.
Esperar.
If that's the case,
Si ese es el caso,
why didn't you follow the order
¿Por qué no seguiste la orden?
and go to Shangyi to find my father
y voy a Shangyi a encontrar a mi padre
after you were injured?
¿Después de que usted resultó herido?
I wanted to.
Yo quería.
But I heard that the king fell into a coma.
Pero oí que el rey cayó en coma.
After he woke up,
Después de despertarse,
it was like he was a different person.
Era como si fuera una persona diferente.
The kind was brilliant.
El tipo era brillante.
After he woke up, he became corrupted.
Después de despertarse, se corrompió.
He put the sages in charge of court affairs.
Puso a los sabios a cargo de los asuntos de la corte.
I've heard about it.
He oído hablar de ello.
I felt odd.
Me sentí extraño.
I...
I...
I even had doubts
Incluso tuve dudas
about that mission.
Sobre esa misión.
I've been secretly investigating for a long time.
He estado investigando en secreto durante mucho tiempo.
I suspected
Yo sospechaba
there was no treasure at all.
No había ningún tesoro en absoluto.
No treasure?
¿No hay tesoro?
What else could there be?
¿Qué más podría haber?
Maybe...
Tal vez...
Maybe that's a secret
Tal vez eso sea un secreto
about making the country stable.
sobre cómo hacer que el país sea estable.
When I found out things weren't that simple,
Cuando me di cuenta de que las cosas no eran tan sencillas,
I made a decision.
Tomé una decisión.
I would hide.
Me escondería.
Maybe I wasn't the only one
Quizás no fui el único
who survived.
que sobrevivieron.
I wanted to wait for those who had the treasure
Quería esperar a los que tenían el tesoro.
to show up first,
aparecer primero,
see what would happen to them,
ver qué les pasaría,
and then make a plan.
y luego hacer un plan.
You didn't think you'd wait 20 years.
No pensaste que esperarías 20 años.
Yeah.
Sí.
Twenty years.
Veinte años.
After I got married here
Después de casarme aquí
and had a son,
y tuvo un hijo,
I forgot my mission back then.
Olvidé mi misión en aquel entonces.
So,
Entonces,
that's the truth of the day.
Esa es la verdad del día.
Well.
Bien.
Do you have the Painting of Luan?
¿Tienes la pintura de Luan?
Since I've been hiding my identity for over 20 years,
Como he estado ocultando mi identidad durante más de 20 años,
I won't carry this important thing with me.
No llevaré esta cosa importante conmigo.
I kept the Painting of Luan in a secret place.
Guardé la pintura de Luan en un lugar secreto.
And I set traps to protect it.
Y puse trampas para protegerlo.
Without the map,
Sin el mapa,
those who enter the cave will be killed by countless arrows.
Aquellos que entren en la cueva serán asesinados por innumerables flechas.
My wife and son have the map.
Mi esposa y mi hijo tienen el mapa.
But they were captured by the Jibei Chamber of Commerce.
Pero fueron capturados por la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei.
If you want the Painting of Luan,
Si quieres el Cuadro de Luan,
please rescue my wife and son.
Por favor rescata a mi esposa y a mi hijo.
You tricked us before.
Ya nos engañaste antes.
Now, you want to use us to rescue your wife and son.
Ahora, quieres usarnos para rescatar a tu esposa y a tu hijo.
You're not sincere.
No eres sincero
I...
I...
Gu Tian is right.
Gu Tian tiene razón.
You should hand over the Painting of Luan to Fu Sheng.
Deberías entregarle la pintura de Luan a Fu Sheng.
How can you make a condition?
¿Cómo puedes poner una condición?
It's my fault.
Es mi culpa.
But I don't have any other choice.
Pero no tengo otra opción.
Please.
Por favor.
Please rescue my wife and son.
Por favor rescata a mi esposa y a mi hijo.
Mr. Meng.
Sr. Meng
We will try
Lo intentaremos
to help you.
para ayudarte
We have to know where they are
Tenemos que saber dónde están.
before we can rescue them.
antes de que podamos rescatarlos.
Forget it.
Olvídalo.
I'll check it out
Lo comprobaré
tonight.
esta noche.
I'll go with you.
Iré contigo.
I forbid you to go.
Te prohíbo que vayas.
If Sun Siming finds out,
Si Sun Siming se entera,
you'll have a problem.
Tendrás un problema.
It's a matter of human lives.
Es una cuestión de vidas humanas.
Let's rescue them first.
Vamos a rescatarlos primero.
Fu Sheng, listen to her.
Fu Sheng, escúchala.
Don't go.
No te vayas.
I forbid you to go as well.
Te prohíbo que vayas también.
If you get caught,
Si te atrapan,
we have to exchange the Bird Jade Plate for you.
Tenemos que cambiarte la placa de jade de pájaro.
You can't go.
No puedes ir
You're going
Te vas
over my dead body.
sobre mi cadáver.
Look at the situation.
Mira la situación.
All right.
Está bien.
You don't have to argue.
No tienes por qué discutir.
I'll go.
yo iré
It's just probing.
Es solo una prueba.
I can do it.
Puedo hacerlo.
But it has nothing to do with you.
Pero no tiene nada que ver contigo.
We can't get you involved.
No podemos involucrarte.
I'm the right person to go.
Soy la persona adecuada para ir.
The others don't know the relationship
Los demás no conocen la relación.
between the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion and you.
entre el Pabellón que captura rumores y usted.
Compared to you,
En comparación contigo,
it will be easier for me
Será más fácil para mí
to get out
salir
if I am discovered by the Chamber of Commerce.
Si soy descubierto por la Cámara de Comercio.
He's been working with me for years.
Él ha estado trabajando conmigo durante años.
He can protect himself.
Él puede protegerse a sí mismo.
All right.
Está bien.
That's a deal.
Es un trato.
Thank you.
Gracias.
[Jibei Chamber of Commerce]
[Cámara de Comercio de Jibei]
I thought it was a big fish.
Pensé que era un pez grande.
It turned out to be you.
Resultó ser usted.
It's a trap.
Es una trampa.
What did you think?
¿Qué te pareció?
The Hearsay-capturing Pavilion
El pabellón que captura rumores
is not that good.
No es tan bueno.
What can you do with me?
¿Qué puedes hacer conmigo?
I had to let you go in the morning.
Tuve que dejarte ir por la mañana.
But now you handed yourself over.
Pero ahora te entregaste.
You broke into the Jibei Chamber of Commerce and meant no good.
Irrumpiste en la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei y no tenías buenas intenciones.
What do you think I'm going to do with you?
¿Qué crees que voy a hacer contigo?
Arrest him.
Arréstalo.
Split up.
Partir.
I guess
Supongo
he's about to catch a man.
Está a punto de atrapar a un hombre.
Yin Lie won't miss it again.
Yin Lie no se lo perderá nunca más.
I don't know if it's Fu Sheng
No sé si es Fu Sheng
or Gu Tian.
o Gu Tian.
I have a good relationship with them.
Tengo una buena relación con ellos.
It doesn't matter which one it is.
No importa cuál sea.
They will end up
Ellos terminarán
meeting each other after death.
Encontrarse después de la muerte.
Sun Siming.
Sol Siming.
You're evil.
Eres malvado
Luckily, I'm not your friend.
Por suerte, no soy tu amigo.
Friend?
¿Amigo?
My Lord will come to Xichuan soon.
Mi Señor vendrá pronto a Xichuan.
He asked us
Él nos preguntó
to clear all obstacles.
Para eliminar todos los obstáculos.
My Lord is coming.
Mi Señor viene.
What are you so happy about?
¿De qué estás tan feliz?
If you can't get the things before My Lord comes,
Si no puedes conseguir las cosas antes de que venga mi Señor,
what do you think will happen to you?
¿Qué crees que te va a pasar?
I won't let My Lord down.
No defraudaré a mi Señor.
When My Lord gets the Jade Plate and the Painting of Luan,
Cuando mi Señor reciba la Placa de Jade y la Pintura de Luan,
he will value you more, right?
Él te valorará más, ¿verdad?
Of course.
Por supuesto.
When everything is taken care of,
Cuando todo esté cuidado,
My Lord will lead the Jibei Army
Mi Señor dirigirá el Ejército de Jibei
to Xichuan.
a Xichuan.
What?
¿Qué?
Who's there?
¿Quién está ahí?
It is top secret that My Lord is coming to Xichuan.
Es un secreto a voces que mi Señor vendrá a Xichuan.
It must not be disclosed.
No debe ser divulgado.
We must kill him.
Debemos matarlo.
I wanted to take
Yo quería tomar
the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion.
El pabellón que captura los rumores.
But you know too much.
Pero sabes demasiado.
You talk too much nonsense.
Hablas demasiadas tonterías.
What are you looking for?
¿Qué estás buscando?
The Hearsay-capturing Pavilion has three thousand detectives.
El pabellón de captura de rumores cuenta con tres mil detectives.
He should have a list on him.
Debería tener una lista consigo.
Why would he
¿Por qué lo haría?
carry such an important thing with him?
¿Llevar algo tan importante consigo?
Because it's important,
Porque es importante,
he would carry it with him.
Lo llevaría consigo.
Feng Qianli.
Feng Qian Li.
You're smart.
Eres inteligente
You are hiding the list
Estás ocultando la lista
under your skin.
debajo de tu piel.
Sun Siming.
Sol Siming.
What are you doing?
¿Qué estás haciendo?
Ms. Chairman.
Señora Presidenta.
I'll keep you in suspense.
Te mantendré en suspenso.
I will
lo haré
play a trick for you.
jugarte una mala pasada
Someone.
Alguien.
Bring me a pot of boiling water.
Tráeme una olla con agua hirviendo.
Yes.
Sí.
Ms. Chairman.
Señora Presidenta.
Look carefully.
Mira con atención.
[The list of three thousand detectives at the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion]
[La lista de tres mil detectives en el Pabellón de Captura de Rumores]
Um...
Uno...
This is...
Esto es...
The list of three thousand detectives at the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion.
La lista de tres mil detectives en el Pabellón de Captura de Rumores.
[The list of three thousand detectives at the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion]
[La lista de tres mil detectives en el Pabellón de Captura de Rumores]
[The animals in the show are props]
[Los animales del espectáculo son accesorios]
[No animals were harmed during the filming]
[Ningún animal resultó dañado durante el rodaje]
♪Under the sky, light and shadow go together♪
♪Bajo el cielo, la luz y la sombra van juntas♪
♪The reflection of prosperity and splendor♪
♪El reflejo de la prosperidad y el esplendor♪
♪Hides many secrets♪
♪Esconde muchos secretos♪
♪It's like♪
♪Es como♪
♪Every page of your life♪
♪Cada página de tu vida♪
♪It's all about destiny♪
♪Todo es cuestión del destino♪
♪The story has tragedy and comedy♪
♪La historia tiene tragedia y comedia♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪Para descubrir el misterio♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪Nos vamos de aventuras♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪No huimos ni nos comprometemos fácilmente♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪Cuando llega el amanecer♪
♪The light shines♪
♪La luz brilla♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪Seguimos el camino del descubrimiento♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪Para perseguir y dar la bienvenida♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪Cada historia desconocida♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪Hacemos un viaje juntos♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪Con sangre caliente y propósito original♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪Aprovechamos el día y lo vivimos al máximo♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪Deja una huella en nuestro viaje♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪Dispersa la oscuridad con nuestros corazones♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪Aspira a marcar la diferencia♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪Para descubrir el misterio♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪Nos vamos de aventuras♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪No huimos ni nos comprometemos fácilmente♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪Cuando llega el amanecer♪
♪The light shines♪
♪La luz brilla♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪Seguimos el camino del descubrimiento♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪Para perseguir y dar la bienvenida♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪Cada historia desconocida♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪Hacemos un viaje juntos♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪Con sangre caliente y propósito original♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪Aprovechamos el día y lo vivimos al máximo♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪Deja una huella en nuestro viaje♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪Dispersa la oscuridad con nuestros corazones♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪Aspira a marcar la diferencia♪
♪Make a difference♪
♪Haz la diferencia♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪Hacemos un viaje juntos♪
♪Through hardships♪
♪A través de las dificultades♪
♪We will find the glory♪
♪Encontraremos la gloria♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪Aspira a marcar la diferencia♪